DAY 1

Good morning everyone.
My name is Yash Pasrija. I am currently pursuing BTech from Amity University Noida. I am first year student of CSE branch.

Task 1

1. What do u mean by git and github?
Ans-
Git - It's a distributed version control system. Means it's keeps track of the history of the project in the local machine. One of The key features is collaboration. It allows two or more people to work together on the same project at the same time.
Github - It can be considered as a web cider or a kind of service. It provides a bed based graphic interface to perform git taks.

2. Why is GitHub do popular and used in most of the projects?
Ans - GitHub is an open-source repository hosting service, sort of like a cloud for code. It hosts your source code projects in a variety of different programming languages and keeps track of the various changes made to every iteration.

3. What is version control system? How is git a VCS?
Ans - VCS - Version Control System is basically a tool that helps to keep track of the changes in the project. It also keeps each team member working on the project at latest version.
      Git is a distributed VCS as it allows the user to keep a local repository of the work in their local system. It is responsible for tracking all the changes and history of the project.

4. What are the other platforms similar to GitHub?
Ans -✓Gitlab
     ✓launchpad
     ✓Bitbucket
     ✓Gitcracken
     ✓SourceForge

5. Why are u interested in learning of git and github?
Ans - Git and github provides is interesting in the way of project handling. Also, since I want to learn new things and this is interesting I am curious to know more about it and it's functions...

Regards
Yash


DAY 2

Good morning everyone...
Here is the link to my repository
 https://github.com/yash3110/git-yash.git

a)How git workflow works?
Ans - The main idea behind the  Workflow is that all feature development  should take place in a dedicated branch instead of the master branch. This encapsulation makes it easy for various  developers to work on a particular feature without disturbing the main codebase. We have  one central repository. Each developer clones the repository and locally made changes in the code and commit it and then pushes  it to the central repository so that the  other developers can  pull and use in their work.

b)What're the different stages of a git project as commit, add?
Ans - Git Workflow consist of the following:
•	Workspace(also known as Working Directory)
•	Index(also known as Stage)
•	Local Repository(also known as Head)
•	Remote Repository
  git clone is a Git command line utility which is used to target an existing repository and create a clone, or    copy of the target repository.
Add command adds the file from working directory to the index .
Furthur if we need to commit it in local repository we use commit command .
Commit  –a command is used to simply commit and stage at once.
push command is used to push the changes  from local to remote repository.
fetch command is used to get  the file from remote to local repository.
merge command takes changes  from local repository to workspace.
pull command will collect the changes from the remote repository then will be taken into  local repository and further into workspace in one go.

c) Is it possible to do a git commit before git add . if you have made any changes? Explain why?
Ans - No, it is not possible because first we add file to stage and then we undergo commit or save it into local repository.

d) Why is git diff used?
This command is used to check the difference between the files in the stage and in the workspace.

e) Can we leave the commit message as blank?
Ans - Yes we can do it by using the below command :
git commit -a --allow-empty-message -m ""